Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Ethereum Application Gathering hosted by Ethereum Application Guild, aka EAG,
女士们先生们，欢迎来到由以太坊应用程序协会（又名 EAG）主办的以太坊应用程序聚会，
a global non-profit collaborative organization dedicated to advancing the innovation, adoption, and real-world impact of the Ethereum native applications.
一个全球非营利协作组织，致力于推进以太坊本机应用程序的创新、采用和现实世界影响。
I'm today's MC Yu Yan, and I'll be with you all day.
我是今天的MC于言，我会陪伴大家一整天。
The Ethereum infrastructure has reached a new level of maturity, and the focus is increasingly shifting towards applications.
以太坊基础设施已经达到了新的成熟度，并且焦点越来越转向应用程序。
Today, we will have a four-chapter discussion towards where momentum is forming, what challenges remain, and how applications are beginning to take shape in practice.
今天，我们将进行四章讨论，讨论动力正在形成的地方、仍然存在的挑战以及应用程序如何在实践中开始成形。
Let's start with Chapter 1, From Infrastructure to Applications, Ethereum's Next Phase.
让我们从第一章开始，从基础设施到应用程序，以太坊的下一阶段。
We will have an overview of the latest developments across Ethereum, its key infrastructure layers, and how these advances are shaping readiness for real-world applications.
我们将概述以太坊的最新发展、其关键基础设施层，以及这些进步如何为现实世界的应用做好准备。
Our first chapter will kick off with an inspiring opening speech by Dr. Xiao Feng, Chairman of Wan Xiang Blockchain, Chairman and CEO of Hashkey Group.
我们的第一章将以万向区块链董事长、Hashkey集团董事长兼首席执行官肖峰博士鼓舞人心的开幕致辞拉开帷幕。
Please welcome the Chairman of Wan Xiang Blockchain, Chairman and CEO of Hashkey Group, Dr. Xiao Feng, to give us his opening speech. Please welcome.
请万向区块链董事长、Hashkey集团董事长兼首席执行官肖峰博士为我们致开幕词。请欢迎。
Good morning, everyone. Welcome to the Ethereum Application Gathering hosted by EAG.
大家早上好。欢迎来到 EAG 主办的以太坊应用聚会。
The Ethereum Application Gathering, EAG, originated in 2014.
以太坊应用程序聚会（EAG）起源于 2014 年。
In 2014, I made a judgment, which I later shared with many of my friends,
2014年，我做了一个判断，后来我和很多朋友分享了，
that blockchain technology has entered the Internet's 1950s.
区块链技术已经进入互联网的20世纪50年代。
That is to say, blockchain technology has developed enough to support large-scale commercial applications.
也就是说，区块链技术已经发展到足以支持大规模商业应用。
We know that most of the Internet platforms, we are now familiar with the Internet platforms,
我们知道大部分的互联网平台，我们现在熟悉的互联网平台，
were actually born between 1995 and 2005.
实际上出生于1995年至2005年之间。
In addition to Amazon, which was founded in 1994, most of the applications were created in the 1950s.
除了 1994 年成立的亚马逊之外，大多数应用程序都是在 20 世纪 50 年代创建的。
So the real large-scale applications of the Internet started in 1995.
所以互联网真正的大规模应用是从1995年开始的。
There are several conditions for the emergence of the Internet in 1995.
1995年互联网的出现有几个条件。
First of all, if the computer's control system, operating system, is still DAO,
首先，如果计算机的控制系统，操作系统，仍然是DAO，
and if it interacts with the computer by command line,
如果它通过命令行与计算机交互，
I believe there will not be a big outbreak of Internet applications.
我相信互联网应用不会出现大爆发。
Later, from the DAO browser, there was a dialogue box,
后来，从DAO浏览器中，出现了一个对话框，
and then developed a graphics operating system.
然后开发了图形操作系统。
The graphics operating system is like Windows.
图形操作系统类似于Windows。
It allows more people to interact with computers in a more convenient way.
它让更多的人以更便捷的方式与计算机交互。
With this condition, with the development of technology,
有了这个条件，随着科技的发展，
Internet applications have only just begun to appear.
互联网应用才刚刚开始出现。
Of course, there are other conditions, including bandwidth,
当然还有其他条件，包括带宽、
a construction of communication facilities.
通讯设施建设。
So the reason why I say that since 2004,
所以我之所以这么说，是从2004年开始，
the blockchain has also entered a time when such an application broke out
区块链也进入了这样一个应用爆发的时代
is because at that time, many technologies of the blockchain,
是因为当时区块链的很多技术，
some application tools, some mechanisms and means of construction of infrastructure,
一些应用工具，一些基础设施建设的机制和手段，
have also begun to be able to use some commercial applications.
也开始能够使用一些商业应用程序。
So I made such a judgment at that time.
所以我当时就做出了这样的判断。
So, of course, in addition to this judgment,
所以，当然，除了这个判断之外，
we also continue to discuss with people in the entire ecosystem
我们也持续和整个生态系统的人一起讨论
and people with application scenarios
以及有应用场景的人
how to establish such a commercial application on the blockchain.
如何在区块链上建立这样一个商业应用。
So last year, in the second half of the year,
所以去年下半年，
in Singapore, we launched the ETAFORM application alliance, EAG.
在新加坡，我们推出了ETAFORM应用联盟EAG。
The ETAFORM's title, this abbreviation,
ETAFORM 的标题，这个缩写，
is because we discussed with the founder of ETAFORM, Vitalik,
是因为我们和ETAFORM的创始人Vitalik讨论过，
what kind of abbreviation would be better?
什么样的缩写会更好？
In fact, Vitalik should be the name for this name.
其实这个名字应该是Vitalik。
Vitalik is of course very supportive of us
Vitalik 当然非常支持我们
to launch such a global application alliance.
发起这样一个全球应用联盟。
So another background of EAG's establishment
那么EAG成立的另一个背景
is that we have had a community activity in ETAFORM
就是我们在ETAFORM有过一个社区活动
called the Three Seas House since 2024 and 2025.
自2024年和2025年起称为三海屋。
The Three Seas House was in Singapore last year in 2025.
三海之家去年2025年在新加坡。
There were dozens of global developers
全球开发者有数十家
gathered in Singapore for a month
相聚新加坡一个月
to discuss various applications on ETAFORM.
讨论 ETAFORM 上的各种应用。
More than 18 African developers came to Singapore
超过18家非洲开发商来到新加坡
during the Three Seas House event in Singapore last year.
去年新加坡三海屋活动期间。
Most of the African developers,
大多数非洲开发商，
these 18 African developers, came to Asia for the first time,
这18位非洲开发商，首次来到亚洲，
even walked out of Africa for the first time.
甚至第一次走出非洲。
In addition to the event in Singapore last year,
除了去年在新加坡举行的活动外，
there was also a three-seas house event in Thailand in 2024.
2024年泰国还有一场三海之家活动。
It also gathered dozens and nearly hundreds of ETAFORM developers,
还聚集了数十、近百名ETAFORM开发者，
especially application developers,
尤其是应用程序开发人员，
to gather together and discuss with each other
to gather together and discuss with each other
for a month.
一个月。
This is also the foundation of ETAFORM's application alliance.
这也是ETAFORM应用联盟的基础。
The Three Seas House has been in operation for three consecutive years.
三海屋已连续运营三年。
The first one in 2023 was in China,
2023年的第一个是在中国，
in a relatively cool place in the northeast of China.
在中国东北相对凉爽的地方。
There was also a month's time.
还有一个月的时间。
In the second half of 2023,
2023年下半年，
almost 300 people arrived at the site.
almost 300 people arrived at the site.
Some people stayed for one or two weeks and left.
有些人呆了一两周就离开了。
Some people stayed longer.
有些人停留的时间更长。
Basically, based on these two foundations,
基本上，基于这两个基础，
one is that we think that ETAFORM technology has arrived
一是我们认为ETAFORM技术已经到来
and can support large-scale commercial applications.
并且可以支持大规模的商业应用。
The other is that in the past two, three, four, five years,
另外就是在过去的两年、三年、四年、五年里，
we have done some specific things in the form of the Three Seas House.
我们以三海之家的形式做了一些具体的事情。
In the third quarter, the influence of the Three Seas House
第三季三海楼影响力
has even exceeded that of Asia.
甚至超过了亚洲。
It has already had a very, very big impact in Africa.
它已经在非洲产生了非常非常大的影响。
So next, ETAFORM,
接下来，ETAFORM，
we are planning to do an ETAFORM event in Africa,
我们计划在非洲举办 ETAFORM 活动，
to really mobilize the African developers.
真正调动非洲开发商的积极性。
This is the origin of ETAFORM
这就是ETAFORM的由来
and the preparation work that we have done before.
以及我们之前所做的准备工作。
This afternoon at 4.30 p.m.,
今天下午4点30分，
we had a one-and-a-half-hour chat with Vittaric.
我们与 Vittaric 进行了一个半小时的交谈。
What we want to discuss is the application of ETAFORM.
我们要讨论的是ETAFORM的应用。
From his point of view and from my point of view,
从他的角度和我的角度来看，
we want to discuss the future applications of ETAFORM.
我们想讨论ETAFORM的未来应用。
What may be the trend, what may be the scenario,
趋势可能是什么，场景可能是什么，
what may be the construction of the infrastructure.
基础设施建设可能是什么？
Yesterday, we also announced that
昨天我们还宣布
the three major technologies,
三大技术，
the blockchain, the zero-sensitivity certification,
区块链、零敏感认证、
and the global encryption,
和全局加密，
after combining these three technologies,
将这三种技术结合起来后，
may bring a subversive innovation
可能会带来颠覆性的创新
to the intelligent economy.
向智能经济迈进。
We know that, like the zero-sensitivity certification,
我们知道，就像零敏感性认证一样，
the formal verification,
形式验证，
these topics have actually been discussed
这些话题实际上已经被讨论过
by the community of ETAFORM since 2016.
自 2016 年起受到 ETAFORM 社区的欢迎。
I remember very clearly that in October 2016,
我记得很清楚，2016年10月的时候，
the global development conference of ETAFORM was held in Shanghai.
ETAFORM全球发展大会在上海召开。
It was held in Shanghai by Dewekang.
由德威康在上海举办。
In the two consecutive days of the ETAFORM global development conference,
在连续两天的ETAFORM全球开发大会上，
several technical experts have actually been discussing
几位技术专家其实一直在讨论
the formal verification, the zero-sensitivity certification,
形式验证、零敏感性认证、
and how to combine these tools,
以及如何结合这些工具，
or the technology of privacy protection,
或者隐私保护技术，
with the blockchain technology.
与区块链技术。
Over the past ten years, we have seen that
过去十年，我们看到
the technologies of the zero-sensitivity certification,
零敏感性认证技术，
and the technology of the global encryption,
以及全球加密技术，
are gradually approaching or entering
正在逐渐接近或进入
a stage where they can support large-scale commercial applications.
到了可以支持大规模商业应用的阶段。
The optimization of the algorithm
算法的优化
needs to be accelerated by hardware.
需要硬件加速。
It needs to have a wider bandwidth.
它需要有更宽的带宽。
After spending ten years,
经过十年的努力，
the technologies of the zero-sensitivity certification
零敏感性认证技术
are gradually beginning to be able to support
正在逐渐开始能够支持
a large-scale application
大规模应用
based on the combination of the blockchain and AI.
基于区块链和人工智能的结合。
In my speech yesterday,
在我昨天的演讲中，
I specifically gave an example
我专门举了一个例子
of how the combination of these three technologies
如何结合这三种技术
can subvert the existing business.
可以颠覆现有的业务。
I gave an example of the hospital.
我举了一个医院的例子。
This example is easier for everyone to understand.
这个例子大家比较容易理解。
The hospital data, its medical data,
医院数据，它的医疗数据，
its medical case,
它的医疗案例，
is absolutely very, very valuable data.
绝对是非常非常有价值的数据。
But if the hospital only has its data without AI,
但如果医院只有数据而没有人工智能，
then it cannot turn data into a token.
那么它就无法将数据转化为令牌。
If it cannot become a token,
如果它不能成为代币，
it is difficult to be called by others.
很难被别人称呼。
But if only AI turns it into a token,
但如果人工智能把它变成代币，
then it faces a problem that
那么它面临的问题是
the hospital data has a very high requirement
医院数据要求非常高
for privacy protection.
以保护隐私。
What is the requirement for privacy protection?
隐私保护有什么要求？
It needs the zero-sensitivity certification,
需要零敏感性认证，
the privacy protection,
隐私保护，
and the privacy computing technology
和隐私计算技术
to support it.
支持它。
Because the medical data
因为医疗数据
cannot be tolerated
不能容忍
and can be easily leaked.
并且很容易泄露。
But if only the zero-sensitivity certification
但如果只是零敏感认证
or the privacy protection,
或者隐私保护，
the privacy computing technology
隐私计算技术
like the privacy encryption,
比如隐私加密，
is still not enough.
还是不够。
Of course, it is already enough.
当然，这已经足够了。
Because if only AI
因为如果只有人工智能
and these privacy computing technologies
以及这些隐私计算技术
can be combined,
可以组合，
then what will happen?
那么会发生什么呢？
If we want to use the data token
如果我们想使用数据令牌
of a hospital,
一家医院的，
we need to negotiate
我们需要谈判
with the relevant departments
会同有关部门
of the hospital
医院的
offline,
离线,
sign contracts,
签订合同，
and pay.
并付款。
This is obviously not beneficial to the hospital.
这显然对医院没有好处。
Unless the hospital establishes
除非医院规定
a huge business operating system
庞大的商业操作系统
to sell its own data,
出售自己的数据，
it is obviously not beneficial to the hospital
显然对医院没有好处
to expand its business
扩大业务
in a token factory.
在代币工厂里。
If it can add blockchain technology
如果可以加入区块链技术
like Bitcoin,
就像比特币一样，
like Ethereum,
就像以太坊一样，
to become a business
成为一家企业
that does not need to be trusted
不需要被信任
and allowed,
并允许，
then the token factory
然后是令牌工厂
of a hospital
医院的
with all medical data
包含所有医疗数据
can be used
可以使用
without the trust
没有信任
of the hospital.
医院的。
It can be used by people
它可以被人们使用
and by global
并通过全球
developers
开发商
and demanders.
和需求者。
This is obviously a better
这显然是一个更好的
and can reach
并且可以达到
a wider range
更广泛的范围
of demanders
需求者数量
in a new business model.
在新的商业模式中。
This is what we said yesterday.
这就是我们昨天所说的。
So we have been discussing
所以我们一直在讨论
about
关于
how to
如何
create a new business model
创造新的商业模式
with the support
在支持下
of other technologies
其他技术的
on Ethereum.
在以太坊上。
So,
所以，
today,
今天，
at this moment,
此时此刻，
EAG
EAG
in the year 2026,
2026年，
has strengthened
已加强
our confidence.
我们的信心。
The blockchain
区块链
in the year
当年